# Paterne MALLE

# Web Developer

paternmalle@gmail.com

07 832 959 448

Leeds, UK

French web-developer, graduated recently, following an intensive one year course, including a three month internship. Looking to put my technical skills and life experience to work in a team environment interested in someone with a non-standard professional path.

#### Main tech skills

Html, CSS, Javascript, React JS, Git, API.

### Soft skills

Teamwork, Adaptability, Autonomy, Critical thinking, Quantitative skills, Analysis, Synthesis.

### Other tech skills

PHP, Laravel, WordPress, Node, PWA, Bootstrap.

## Languages

English: proficient.French: native.

# **Education**

Web developer: 2019 - 2020 Simplon school, Level 5 equivalent

- Contents of the course: Html, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Git, Node, PHP, Laravel, SQL, WordPress, PWA.
- Learned the basics of SEO and web design.
- · Introduction to agile methodologies.
- Opquast certified: good practises for web (UX, accessibility, security, e-commerce).
- · Hands on and practical exercises.
- Realised multiple small projects in teams of three to four people.
- Presentations in front of public varying from the class to 50 people.

## BPREA Poultry farming: 2011 A level equivalent

- Two, one month practical internships.
- Learned technical and economic skills for enterprise management.

## CAP Carpentry: 2008 NVQ level 2 equivalent

- · Two, one month practical internships.
- Workflow conception, process organization.
- Fine-tuned attention to detail and creative problem solving skills.

Master's degree in sociology: 2001 - 2006 University of Caen.

- · Developed self-discipline.
- · Critical thinking, documenting.
- · Survey design, data gathering and analysis.

# Work experience

# Practical Internship (3 months): 2020 Com3elles.

Small communication company, specialized in design, advice, and website conception using the CMS Joomla! and WordPress.

- Improved a Joomla! component (changing a data typology into another one).
- Enhanced a plugin for Joomla!, using Googlemap, Openstreetmap, Leaflet and Algolia.
- Skills developed: autonomy, research, dealing with legacy code.

## Cheese maker: 2017 - 2018 Artisanal cheese factory

- Elected staff representative for 30 employees.
- · Reorganized aspects of the manufacturing processes.
- Skills developed: teamwork, responsiveness, improvisation and crisis management.

# Farmer and woodworker: 2008 - 2017 Collaborative homestead

- · Created and managed an organic free range egg workshop of 450 hens.
- Built a new 400m<sup>2</sup> sheepfold.
- Lived, worked and decided as a team, fluctuating between 5 and 12 members.
- Responsible for client relation/sales with professionals and customers.
- Skills developed: teamwork, autonomy, adaptation, improvisation, constancy.

# Personal projects

Link to my Github: https://github.com/Patern14

#### Pokedex

- · Created with React JS and react-router-dom.
- Retrieves data from pokeAPI.
- Displays the first 20 Pokemons, load the following 20, displays a random Pokemon.
- Shows details of the selected Pokemon including their types and evolutions.

### Flexbox reminder

- · DOM manipulation with Javascript.
- An interactive reminder for Flexbox properties where the results of the different options for the Container and the Content are displayed.

## Sm4rty

- Reproduced the Smarty website homepage.
- Media queries for desktop and mobile versions.

## Connect4

- A Javascript version of the four in a row game.
- · Victory conditions, reset button.

### Interests

Sciences, technologies, UI/UX, Boardgames, Woodworking, Ecology, Sports, Japan, USA, History.